Take me to Kirito.
Well, there you go.
I told you your boy was the biggest
threat to this project's security.
I know.
You don't have to rub it in.
Is Kirito even safe here?
Were you lying when you
said you could save him?
Is he alive? Answer me!
Kanamoto injected a potent toxin into him.
It damaged Kirito's brain so much,
conventional treatment can't heal him.
But, unconventional treatment can, and the
only place with that technology is wrath.
I'm sure he told you about it.
The STL, short for Soul Translator.
If we use the STL to
stimulate his Fluctlight,
we can regenerate a brand new,
perfectly healthy neural network.
But that takes time.
Right now, he's in a full-spec
STL, which can only be found here.
The treatment he's getting surpasses
what any hospital can offer.
He even has his own full-time nurse.
Okay, then.
I'll take your word for it.
All right, Kikwoka.
Since you're in the mood to talk,
might as well tell us everything.
From the top.
First, why is an SDF official like
you using the Ministry as a front?
Next, what's the point of this?
And last, why Kirigaya specifically?
If you want answers,
you'll have to sign on.
How about you start talking?
All right, then.
I assume you're both familiar
with the concept of the STL?
It reads souls,
or Fluctlights as you call them,
and allows the user to dive into a
virtual world that's incredibly lifelike.
That's correct.
And do you know what the
objective of this project is?
No, I don't.
To create a bottom-up, multi-purpose
artificial intelligence.
Let's go ahead and go ahead
and get out of the way!.
I hear a voice that I call?.
To your fingers.
I'm starting to see the end of the call.
I'm going to see the end of the call!.
Shiny song, my diamond.
I'm going to cry and cry.
I'm going to cry?.
A bottom-up, multi-purpose AI?
That's right.
There are two approaches
to developing an AI.
The first is called top-down
artificial intelligence,
where the AI is programmed with
experience and knowledge so that
it learns enough to approach
something close to true intelligence.
That's pretty much the gist of it.
Everything that's an AI right now
is using that top-down approach.
Heck, Dr.
Shige Mura was working
with us here for a bit,
and even his research focused on that.
A top-down AI, however, can't react
appropriately to things it hasn't learned about.
At this point in time, none have evolved
enough to have true intelligence.
The second approach to AI
development is called Bottom-Up.
The human brain is an
organ comprised of 100
billion cells connected in intricate ways.
The idea of Bottom-Up
is recreating the brain
electronically and generating
true intelligence in it.
But that would be impossible to do.
You're right, and until now, it was.
But with the Soul Translator,
we can scan a human soul.
Or specifically, the quantum field and
brain cells we call the Fluct Light.
If you're wondering where we're going
to put all the data of a human brain,
stop wondering.
We made the Light Quantum
Gate Crystal, or Light Cube,
to store all that good stuff on.
Theoretically, you could save a
one-to-one copy of a Fluct Light.
That's correct.
Although, it's not a theory.
We've already copied a human soul.
But then, why did you bother
asking me to come help you?
Because, like idiots, we missed something.
The human soul is complex.
Sure, we can copy it.
But there's a wide gap
between it and a true AI.
Higa?
Go on.
Show our guests a demonstration.
Damn, you're sadistic.
Is the sampling done yet?
Yep.
No problems.
Looking good.
Sweet.
So why is it dark and
how come I can't move?
Oh I know why.
Let me out.
The stl's glitching.
Sorry buddy I can't log you out.
Dude what the hell?
Let me out of here.
Who are you?
I don't recognize your voice.
Takeru Higa.
You know that?
What?
No way.
I'm Higa.
Let me out and you'll see.
Relax.
You're talking to Higa the copy.
I know.
You know what's going on.
So just accept the situation. Screw you.
I'm me.
If I'm a copy then I know it.
God damn it.
Come on.
Please let me out.
You son of a bitch.
Right now we talked about this.
You need to calm down.
If you can't think rationally your fluk
light won't be able to I am rational!
Okay, then.
Let's see who's faster
at Pi, me or that faker.
Full collapse, one minute, eight seconds.
Alright, that was beyond twisted.
It is disturbing.
Still, it's the best way to explain what
we've been able to accomplish up to now.
I'm sorry you had to see it.
We copied over a dozen
Fluctlights, including mine,
and submitted them to the same test.
The results were always the same.
Their logic systems went
haywire and they collapsed.
Since mature Fluctlights don't
work, what would you try next?
Maybe wipe their memories?
Or raise a soul from scratch.
You didn't.
Yes, we did.
We put newborns into the
STL and copied their souls.
These copies are essentially
human, so how would you raise them?
Not in a void.
You'd need an exact
copy of the real world.
That's impossible.
We can't do that yet.
So, we went looking for an
alternative, and we found it online.
VRMMO Worlds.
Tonkii, you're sharp.
Using the seed, we made our own
world, with villages and terrain,
and converted it to mnemonic
visuals for the STL.
We placed four of our staff in
the first village we created.
They acted as parents to 16 AI infants,
or soul architects, and
raised them till they were 18.
We monitored the
youngsters as they grew up.
Oh, by the way, officially we
call them artificial Fluctlights.
Anyway, we were more than
satisfied with how they turned out.
They were sharp, obedient, and upstanding.
When they eventually paired up,
we made them parents and gave
them new soul archetypes to raise.
Our staff was out by then,
so we accelerated time by 5,000 and
soon we had multiple generations.
After three weeks had passed in our
world, 300 had passed in theirs.
Now, they have a fully functioning
society with a population of 80,000.
You simulated an entire civilization.
Exactly.
So far, 480 years have passed there.
The capital, Senator, has
20,000 citizens living in it.
At this point,
all the AI Fluctlights have matured into
the bottom-up AIs we were shooting for.
We were all ready to hit the next
phase and were stoked about it.
But then...
We noticed a major issue,
which stood in our way.
What issue?
The governing body there
called the Axiom Church
created a set of laws
called the Taboo Index.
The what index?
The Taboo Index.
It contains laws like one forbidding
murder, just like we have.
And, if you've been
watching the news recently,
you can see how difficult that
one is for humans to obey.
But the Fluctlights obey all
their laws to the letter.
They're obsessive about it.
This town is beautiful, but too perfect.
There's no litter on the streets
and no crime to speak of.
Needless to say, there's not been a
single murder committed here either.
And that would be a
good thing, wouldn't it?
It wouldn't.
Not for him, anyway.
He wants AIs that can kill.
Kirito and I were wrong.
We thought we knew why you
were interested in VR Miss.
For training.
We figured you'd use the technology
to train soldiers and police.
But for an officer of the SDF to
attempt something on this scale,
there has to be more at stake.
And there is.
This project is about
creating AI for warfare.
Isn't it?
Is that true, Kikwoka?
Five years ago, when the NerveGear
was first announced, I had an idea.
Although it was meant for gaming,
this new technology had the potential
to change how wars were fought.
When the SAO incident happened,
I asked to be transferred to the Ministry,
then joined the task force there.
That was all so I could get
this project off the ground.
And five years later, here we are.
That's his reason but why did
you decide to take part in this?
Oh, um, that's a whole
nother story for me.
It's personal
When I was in college,
I had a bud in Korea who was in the army
there and he got killed
on one of his tours.
So I thought this stupid world ain't
gonna stop having wars anytime soon!
But if we could figure out how to
have them without killing people then?
Sounds naive, right?
You didn't tell Kirito any of this
before you hired him, did you?
Would it matter if I did?
Yes, it would have.
If you had told him, he never
would have agreed to help.
There's one important issue
your plan doesn't even address.
Which is?
The rights of the AIs.
These things you call
artificial flufflights?
They're still mentally
and emotionally human.
True, but it's not like
they have physical bodies.
But otherwise, they're
no different from us,
and you're forcing them
to be your tools of war.
Kirito would never agree to that. Ever.
Look, I understand the point
you're trying to make here,
but to me,
the life of one SDF soldier is worth
far more than a hundred thousand AIs.
Anyway, why did you
need Kirigaya for this?
I can't understand why you'd use a civilian
on a project that's so confidential.
I'm sorry.
I got so carried away talking
about the project, I almost forgot.
We needed to know why the AI Fluctlights
couldn't disobey the Taboo Index.
So, I came up with an experiment.
If we blocked a human's memories,
reverted him to childhood,
and had him grow up in our VR world,
would he be able to
disobey the Taboo Index?
To carry this out, we needed someone with
experience navigating in a VR environment.
Not just a week or a
month's worth of experience.
I'm talking years.
That's why I needed him.
I can't believe Kazuto would
sign up for something like that.
Can we even trust anything
Kikuoka says anymore?
I bet he only told you a fraction
of what he's really up to.
I guess all we can do now is hope the
treatment Kirito gets in the STL will work.
What happened with that taboo index thing?
You know, the experiment.
Did he tell you if it worked?
Kirito got to be close friends
with two others, a boy and a girl.
Kikuoka said the girl ended
up breaking one of the laws.
Really?
Did she do it because of Kirito? Uh-huh.
Apparently she violated a taboo by
trying to access a restricted address.
According to the log, the girl saw another
AI Fluctlight die in the restricted area.
From what we can tell, she
was trying to save him.
She had more concern for
another person's life
than she had for
disobeying the taboo index.
She chose to do it, and
that's what we're looking for.
That's kind of a neat story.
Yeah, if only it wasn't about
training AIs to kill people.
You're right.
But look at what she did.
She went against the system
just to help someone else.
Does this AI girl have a name? Yes.
Alice? That's right.
I was stunned when I found out.
Her having that name is
quite the coincidence.
The name ALICE, you see,
also happens to be the
name of the concept that
was the foundation for Wrath
and this project. Concept?
An AI that is highly
adaptive and autonomous.
More specifically,
an artificial labile intelligent
cybernated existence, or the acronym ALICE.
Our goal, ultimately, was to turn
an AI Fluctlight into an ALICE.
Therefore, we called
it Project Alicization.
That sounds so complicated!
Yeah, I don't understand a
lot of what he said either.
But he said if they had
saved Alice's floodlight?
Their research would be
much further along by now.
Did she die?
No, she's still alive But remember I
said time there's faster than here?
Mm-hmm
Well, by the time they noticed,
two days had gone by there.
She was taken to the capital, and the
Axiom Church had her Fluctlight altered.
They changed her soul?
How could they give AI Fluctlights
that kind of authority over each other?
They don't really know how it happened, but
they think it might be a system exploit.
A few of the AI Fluctlights can
use what they call sacred arts.
They're basically system access
authorities that look like magic spells.
Sorry I have to log out now?
Why?
What's the rush?
They said they'd let me
look in on Kirito for a bit.
I don't want to be late for that.
You get to watch him sleep.
Tell us if he drools.
I don't.
I don't think I'll see his face.
The machine he sent covers it up.
Number four, and that's five.
They're still building Unit 6.
It's in Roppongi with
Unit 1, the prototype.
Two and three are here.
Well, actually, they're
in the lower shaft.
Ms. Aki.
What are you doing here?
I'm taking care of Kirigaya.
But you were his nurse at
that hospital in Chiyoda.
Wait, are you a nurse
or are you just faking?
I'm a nurse.
I'm registered and everything
and have the papers to prove it.
Although, full disclosure,
the nursing school I graduated from is
affiliated with the Tokyo Self-Defense Force.
Sergeant First Class Natsuki Aki.
As long as I'm on duty here, I swear
I will protect Kitty Gaia. We good?
Yeah, we're good.
Don't you worry about a thing.
In your opinion, will he be okay?
Of course he will.
His Fluctlight's stable so far, and
his neural network's on the mend.
All his vitals are looking good, too.
He is a tough cookie.
He's the one who cleared SAO, after all.
Can we talk?
There's something I
have to confess to you.
Not just to you.
I owe one to all the SAO
players, living and dead.
I'm sure you heard the story
about how during the SAO incident,
Akihiko Kayaba and I were hiding
in the mountains of Nagano.
That scars from a micro-bomb
Akihiko implanted there.
The news said he put it
there to force me to stay
and help him with his plan
during those two years.
But that's not the truth.
Yes, the bomb was real, but
I knew it would never go off.
He put it there so that
when we were caught,
I wouldn't be charged
with aiding and abetting.
It was a bluff to keep me safe, and
the only present he ever gave me.
When Akihiko got into the
Toto Institute of Technology,
he was already head of
development at Argus.
But I didn't know about that.
All I saw was a scrawny loner who
only cared about his research.
You want some inspiration?
Then get out once in a while.
I need to find a way to emulate the
feeling of sunlight on the skin.
What?
We were total opposites,
but we started dating.
One thing I could never figure out
was why he wanted to stay with me.
The other was him.
all that time together.
And I didn't know him at all.
I knew Akihiko was at his cabin, but I
didn't go there because I wanted to help him.
I...
I went because I wanted to kill him.
And then, I don't know why, but I...
I...
I couldn't do it.
He knew what I was thinking,
and that I had a knife.
But he just smiled and said,
What am I going to do with you?
Like he always did.
And then he went back to Aincrad.
Oh God, I'm so sorry.
Kirito and I never blamed you
or hated you for anything.
To tell you the truth.
I can't really say I hate
the commander either.
I mean, Akihiko Kayaba.
I'm not saying he should be
forgiven for what he did.
He shouldn't.
A lot of lives were lost.
But still, and this may
sound a little selfish.
I wouldn't trade anything for the time
I got to spend living there with Kirito.
Honestly, to me, those were
the best days of my life.
Yes, the commander committed a crime.
And so did Kirito and I.
And you did too.
We all did something wrong.
But in the end, even if we're punished,
there's no way to make it right.
I don't think the day will
ever come when we're forgiven.
All we can do is own up to it.
There's no choice but to
face our sins and keep going.
Coming all the way out here?
What am I gonna do with you?
It's so early.
Come back to bed.
Was that?
A dream?
go.
So you are just smiling.
I want to see you when I am.
I want you to protect me.
I want you to feel
I've received my eyes.
I've always seen my eyes on my face.
I've been able to hold my eyes.
It's not a picture of your back.
Game no so no nabushii sa wo.
Iska to Nori de kanji ra Rider.
Kaku Sheyta ita.
So no kizu wo.
Sukoshi ne mo i yasetatara ii na.
Realistu yuuu.
Thank you.